esurance.com 2002-06-10

# Esurance - Privacy and Security

Our privacy commitment   
Information gathering practices   
Verification of information   
Confidential and secure environment   
Collection and use of information   
Information we disclose   
Opt-out provisions   
Email communication   
Cookies  
Demographic information  
Log files   
Site use tracking   
Correcting/updating your information   
Insurance policy activation/cancellation   
Contact information

**Our privacy commitment**  
Esurance values its relationship with you. Protecting the privacy of information we have about you is of great importance to us. We want you to understand how we protect the confidentiality of that information, as well as how and why we use and disclose it. The following provides details of our practices and procedures for protecting the security of non-public personal information about you, while you are our customer and when you are no longer our customer. 

**Information gathering practices**  
At Esurance, we gather a variety of information in order to provide you with insurance services. Our goal is to ask you only for the information we need to deliver the insurance coverage and to meet requirements set by state regulatory agencies. You can obtain an insurance quote in a non-secure environment by providing us with the following information:

  * Your ZIP Code
  * The year, make, and model of the vehicle(s) you'd like to insure
  * Your current insurer, policy expiration date, and annual premium 
  * Years licensed to drive in the U.S. 
  * Years continuously insured 
  * Whether your car is owned, financed, or leased 
  * Information about your driving record (violations or accidents)
  * Your marital status, gender, date of birth, and occupation 
  * Your first name and email address

With this information, we can provide you with an approximate rate of insurance as the driver of the car you specified. If, after you receive a quote you would like to apply for an insurance policy online, you will enter a secure environment where we will request that you provide us with the following additional information:

  * Your full name
  * Mailing address 
  * Telephone number 
  * Driver license number 
  * Vehicle(s) loan or lease information (if applicable) 
  * VIN(s), or Vehicle Identification Numbers for the vehicles listed on your policy 
  * Social Security Number 
  * Credit/debit card number 
  * Expiration date of current coverage
  * The name of your current insurance carrier
  * The policy number of your current insurance policy

We request your name, email address and telephone number so that we can contact you with information on your policy. We need your address, number of years insured, insurance history, driver license number, Social Security Number, and VIN so that we can determine the appropriate rates for your insurance. Information about your car's lienholder is required by law. (If your car is financed, we must notify your lending agency of your insurance information.) Your credit/debit card number is transmitted and stored in an encrypted format in order to process your payments on a regular basis. Information about your current policy allows us to prompt you when your policy nears expiration. We request the previous carrier and policy number, depending upon state regulations, for underwriting purposes to determine the appropriate rate and/or product to offer.

Children (individuals under the age of 13) are not eligible to use our services or the Web site and minors (individuals 13 and older but under the age of 18) should only use the Web site with parental consent. No information about or from children should be provided on the Web site.

**Verification of information**  
If you decide to buy insurance, we will verify personal information you have entered on our site or access additional personal information by contacting other sources. For example, we routinely obtain a copy of your driving record from your state Motor Vehicle Department. In keeping with standard industry practices, Esurance uses the information you have entered on our site to check your driving history, claims history, and credit rating. Your historic insurance claims records are also obtained from the CLUE/Metropolitan Index bureau. Esurance does this to verify that the information you provided in your application is correct and valid.

**Confidential and secure environment**  
Esurance uses leading encryption technology to protect your information. Our Web servers have been enabled with Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to prevent unauthorized parties from viewing personal information provided to Esurance during a secure session.

All secure pages on our Web site have been issued a digital certificate by Secure Server Certification Authority. You can view this digital certificate affirming the security of our site by clicking on the image of the "closed lock" at the bottom of your browser window. A small frame displaying our site's security information will appear. Click on "Subject" to verify that you are on the Esurance site. Click on "Issuer" to verify our site's certification authority.

We restrict access to personal information about you to our employees, our affiliates' employees, or others who need to know that information to service your account. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect your personal information. 

**Collection and use of information**   
All information is collected during the quote and payment process. Telephone representatives completing a transaction collect the same information. This information is used to price, process, and service your insurance policy. Additional information may be collected by telephone or from the Web site if you need to change your policy or file a claim.

All claims information remains confidential and is considered only in reference to the specific claim. Claims information is not provided to third parties unless required by law or as part of Esurance's relationships with claims index bureaus. In accordance with standard insurance fraud protection practices, Esurance provides claims data, which includes your name, address, and Social Security Number to the CLUE/Metropolitan Index Bureau. Information on total losses and auto thefts is provided to the National Insurance Crime Bureau. The information submitted to these claims index bureaus is shared between insurance companies. Other disclosures may be made if required by law. 

Esurance works closely with reliable insurance companies to provide you with insurance products. Our relationship with these companies is governed by an agreement that includes provisions requiring that all customer information shared between our companies be maintained as confidential. (Click here to find out more about the company providing policies in your state.) 

In some cases, visitors enter our site from a partner site where they have already entered personal information. Our partner will pass this personal information to Esurance for the purpose of expediting the navigation through our screens and applications. Before providing this information from a partner site, you will have the ability to opt out of such transfer. If you do not choose to opt out, information such as your address or phone number will be transferred into the forms on our Web site in order to provide you with a convenient purchase process.

In the reverse situation, Esurance will pass your information to partners whose products or services you have indicated may be of interest to you. Before providing this information, Esurance will offer you the ability to opt out of such transfer. If you do not choose to opt out, information such as your address or telephone number will be transferred into the forms on our partner's Web site in order to provide you with a convenient purchase process.

**Information we disclose**  
We may disclose public and non-public personal information about you to the following types of third parties:

  * Financial service providers, such as life insurers, other automobile insurers, mortgage bankers, securities broker-dealers, and insurance agents
  * Non-financial companies, such as retailers, direct marketers, airlines, and publishers
  * Others, such as nonprofit organizations

We may also disclose information about you to non-affiliated third parties as permitted by law. This includes, among other things, disclosures of any information that we collect to companies that perform marketing services on our behalf, or to other financial institutions with which we have joint marketing agreements

**Opt-out provisions**  
If you prefer that we do not disclose public or non-public personal information about you to non-affiliated third parties, you may opt out of those disclosures. That is, you may direct us not to make those disclosures (except those necessary to provide you with our services or others permitted by law). If you wish to opt out of disclosures to non-affiliated third parties, you may contact us by writing or calling our customer service center:

Write to:  
Esurance Customer Service   
P.O. Box 5250  
Sioux Falls, SD 57117-5250

Call:  
Esurance Customer Service at 1-800-926-6012

**Email communication**   
We occasionally work with marketing agencies that provide us with lists of email addresses for individuals we believe will like our products. These agencies may send an email on behalf of Esurance to potential customers. We do not control these addresses and cannot remove addresses from their lists. If you prefer not to receive promotions or solicitations from Esurance via email, please send an email message to [remove@csr.esurance.com](mailto:remove@csr.esurance.com). 

You may also opt out by calling our customer service center at 1-800-926-6012, or sending a letter to the address in the "Contact Section" at the end of this document.  
We will either remove your address from our future email promotions and/or will provide you with the contact information for the marketing companies who own the lists. You can then contact them directly and have your name removed from their lists.

Esurance may email you various items when you get a quote, change or cancel a policy, or when your credit card is charged. Your email address is not required to complete a quote. It is required if you want to create and save the quote in an account. 

**Emails after completing a quote**  
Esurance asks for your email address during the quote process. Your email address is not required to complete a quote. If you do provide your email address and have not purchased a policy, Esurance will send you reminder mail close to the date your current policy expires. You may opt out of future resolicitations at that time by following instructions on the email reminder. Additional contact information is provided at the end of this policy.

**Emails after policy purchase**  
If you purchase insurance, you will have the ability to opt out of third-party information, offers, etc., from Esurance.

Esurance will send you additional email notices relating to your policy such as billing notices, confirmations of changes, modifications to the Esurance privacy statement, changes to our products, and Esurance specific communications. In some cases, your local state laws or insurance regulations may require these communications. You may NOT opt out of the Esurance-specific emails that relate to the primary usage of our service; and you agree to receive these if you make a purchase.

**Customer surveys**  
If you purchase a policy you may receive a survey at some time in the future. Survey data is used to help Esurance maintain a high level of customer service and provide the appropriate products to our customers. There is no obligation to fill out a survey.

**Third-party emails**   
From time to time Esurance may send opted-in users emails related to third-party promotions. We send these emails to the email address you have provided us while on our site. Each email will include the ability to opt out of future notices.

**Cookies:**

**First-party cookies**  
Your browser must be set to accept cookies in order to navigate the Esurance site. We use cookies to securely verify your identity, to enhance site performance, and to personalize aspects of your experience at our site. In addition, cookies let us know how visitors are using our site. In this way we can make your experience on our site faster and better.

**Third-party cookies**  
As part of our efforts to optimize your experience, Esurance does allow third parties to set cookies via our Web site for the purpose of contractual reporting and Web site enhancement. The data gathered from these cookies is used solely for the purposes and in the manner described in this paragraph. Specifically, Esurance uses the services of Matchcraft (www.matchcraft.com), Mediaplex ([www.mediaplex.com](http://www.mediaplex.com/)), Doubleclick ([www.doubleclick.com](http://www.doubleclick.com/)), and Advertising.com ([www.advertising.com](http://www.advertising.com/)).

These services are used to serve Esurance ads on other Web sites. Matchcraft, Mediaplex, Doubleclick, and Advertising.com provide tracking information from online advertising to Esurance. This allows Esurance to see which ads on other sites send us traffic, and if these visitors complete a quote. Esurance gains no personal information on visitors from these services. Customers may opt out from Doubleclick tracking by visiting the Doubleclick Web site at <http://www.doubleclick.com/us/corporate/privacy>. 

Your security is not compromised by the use of these cookies. Our site uses industry standard encryption techniques to send cookies. Our cookies contain no personal information and will not damage your computer or data. 

**Demographic information**   
Esurance provides aggregate demographic information to a limited number of third parties in an effort to develop additional products and services. In no instance, other than those described in the "Cookies" section will this demographic information be specific to you or any other particular person. 

**Log files**  
Esurance logs individual Web site visit information as part of our business tracking. This information is part of our Web site "log files" and tracks the following items:

  * Top referring IP addresses 
  * Top referring ISPs 
  * Browser type 
  * Traffic derived from a partner site 
  * Time and date of visit 

Log files may contain information specific to a quote, but not to an individual (e.g., ZIP Code). No log file information is shared outside of the company and remains part of the policy processing system.

**Site use tracking**   
Some of our partners provide us with aggregate demographic information based on the ZIP Code that our visitors enter on the first page of our site. Aside from that ZIP Code, these partners do not have access to any information about our visitors.

**Correcting/updating your information**  
Esurance customers can update or change personal information at any time on our Web site or by telephone. To make changes online, visit [www.esurance.com](http://www.esurance.com/) and go to the "Your Account" section. Log on with your ID and password, and you will be able to change your information. To make changes by telephone, please call our customer service center at 1-800-926-6012 or send a written notice to the address below:

Esurance Customer Service   
P.O. Box 5250  
Sioux Falls, SD 57117-5250 

**Insurance policy activation/cancellation**  
A policyholder may cancel an Esurance insurance policy at any time by calling customer service at 1-800-926-6012. Esurance may cancel a policyholder's insurance policy under certain circumstances. If Esurance cancels a policy, the customer will be notified in accordance with local state regulations. If a policy is cancelled, information on that policy will be stored by Esurance for a period of seven years or that period required by state law, whichever is shorter. 

**Contact information**  

| Email: | For questions related to your quote or policy, please send email to [support@csr.esurance.com](mailto:support@csr.esurance.com)  
For comments on customer service or this Web site, please click on "Contact Us" in the top navigation bar.  
---|---  
Telephone: | For questions on a quote, coverage options, or purchasing a policy, please call us at 1-800-926-6012.  
Write to: | Esurance Customer Service   
P.O. Box 5250  
Sioux Falls, SD 57117-5250   
  
Please note: As of May 17, 2001, Esurance is no longer a participant in the TrustE program.

Version PN004 effective March 5, 2002
